World War I/Travelogues
Marist Archives and Special Collections
World War I/Travelogues
2.3.9
Marist College
MMM
MMM
MMM
  Box 1636
- World War I/Travelogues, 2.3.9
  - Travelogue poster: “Under the Patronage of H.R.H. The Prince of Wales. With Allenby in Palestine. With Lawrence in Arabia. The Lowell Thomas Travelogues. Including pictures in motion and color”, circa 1919; 1; 11 x 15 color (Box 1636)
  - Graphic of a camel under palm trees from a larger Lowell Thomas travelogue poster. It is an original lithograph on poster board, circa 1919; 2; 16 x 15 b&w (Box 1636)
  - Travelogue window card: “With Lowell Thomas (of Allenby in Palestine fame) ‘Through Romantic India’”; offset lithograph poster, circa 1925; 3; 9 x 11¾ color (Box 1636)
  - Travelogue window card: “’Hindustan’, Through Romantic India, Mr. Lowell Thomas will personally appear at each performance”, circa 1925; 4-6; 12½ x 10 b&w (Box 1636)
  - Travelogue window card: “The Annual Carnagey-Thomas Travelogues. General Allenby’s Campaign in the Holy Land and the Land of the Arabian Nights.”; offset lithograph poster (four different versions), circa 1919; 7-10; 14 x 11 color (Box 1636)
  - Window card advertising “Kaiser’s Helmet and other remarkable trophies brought from Berlin by Lowell Thomas…”, circa 1919; 11; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1636)
  - Travelogue poster: “Lowell Thomas, Mon., Tues., Wed., Thurs., Fri., Sat., Daily 2:30 ,& 8:30, With Allenby in Palestine and Arabia” [Poster was made in two pieces: 25 complete posters, 9 bottom halves], circa 1919; 12-36; 20 x 24 (complete) color (Box 1636)
  Box 1637
- World War I/Travelogues, 2.3.9
  - Travelogue poster for the Lowell Thomas Travelogue: “With Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia”; lithograph 8 panel poster [one panel is missing], circa 1919 - 1920; 1; 96 x 192 color (Box 1637)
  - Large blue travelogue poster: “Thomas Travelogues by Lowell Thomas Himself, With Allenby in Palestine, Covent Garden Royal Opera House”; Morgan Litho Company; 3 panel lithograph poster, circa 1919; 2; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large blue travelogue poster: “Percy Burton Presents, Thomas Travelogues by Lowell Thomas Himself”; Morgan Litho Company; 3 panel lithograph poster, circa 1919; 3; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large blue travelogue poster: “Thomas Travelogues by Lowell Thomas Himself”; Morgan Litho Company; 3 panel lithograph poster, circa 1919; 4; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large blue travelogue poster: “Thomas Travelogues by Lowell Thomas Himself”; Morgan Litho Company; 3 panel lithograph poster, circa 1919; 5; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large blue travelogue poster: “Thomas Travelogues by Lowell Thomas Himself”; Morgan Litho Company; 3 panel lithograph poster [framed and on display in the Special Collections research room], circa 1919; 6; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster with three military men and one woman: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under the Direction of Dale Carnagey, Direct from a Years Run in New York and London”; Morgan Litho Company; 2 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 7; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster with three military men and one woman: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under the Direction of Dale Carnagey, Direct from a Years Run in New York and London”; Morgan Litho Company; 2 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 8; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster with three military men and one woman: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under the Direction of Dale Carnagey, Direct from a Years Run in New York and London”; Morgan Litho Company; 2 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 9; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster with three military men and one woman: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under the Direction of Dale Carnagey, Direct from a Years Run in New York and London”; Morgan Litho Company; 2 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 10; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster with three military men and one woman: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under the Direction of Dale Carnagey, Direct from a Years Run in New York and London”; Morgan Litho Company; 2 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 11; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster with three military men and one woman: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under the Direction of Dale Carnagey, Direct from a Years Run in New York and London”; Morgan Litho Company; 2 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 12; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster with three military men and one woman: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under the Direction of Dale Carnagey, Direct from a Years Run in New York and London”; Morgan Litho Company; 2 panel lithograph poster [framed and on display in the Special Collections research room], circa 1920; 13; 41 x 80 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster of Allenby’s head and men on horses: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under Direction of Dale Carnagey, On No Stage has been Presented Anything More fascinating”; Morgan Litho Company; 5 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 14; 84 x 84 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster of Allenby’s head and men on horses: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under Direction of Dale Carnagey, On No Stage has been Presented Anything More fascinating”; Morgan Litho Company; 5 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 15; 84 x 84 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster of Allenby’s head and men on horses: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under Direction of Dale Carnagey, On No Stage has been Presented Anything More fascinating”; Morgan Litho Company; 5 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 16; 84 x 84 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster of Allenby’s head and men on horses: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under Direction of Dale Carnagey, On No Stage has been Presented Anything More fascinating”; Morgan Litho Company; 5 panel lithograph poster, circa 1920; 17; 84 x 84 color (Box 1637)
  - Large travelogue poster of Allenby’s head and men on horses: “The Lowell Thomas Travelogues with Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia, Under Direction of Dale Carnagey, On No Stage has been Presented Anything More fascinating”; Morgan Litho Company; 5 panel lithograph poster [panel two only], circa 1920; 18; color (Box 1637)
  Box 1638
- World War I/Travelogues, 2.3.9
  - Travelogue poster: “With Allenby in Palestine”; single panel lithograph, 1922; 1; 14 x 1 color (Box 1638)
  - Travelogue poster: “With Allenby in Palestine” at the Tremont Temple; single panel lithograph, 1924; 2-6; 14 x 22 color (Box 1638)
  - Travelogue poster: “With Allenby in Palestine” at the Philharmonic; single panel lithograph, 1923; 7-9; 14 x 22 color (Box 1638)
  - Travelogue poster of Allenby’s head and men on horses: “With Allenby in Palestine”; Morgan Litho Company; single panel lithograph, 1923; 10-15; 21 x 27 color (Box 1638)
  - Travelogue poster of Allenby’s head and men on horses: “With Allenby in Palestine” at the Philharmonic; Morgan Litho Company; single panel lithograph, 1923; 16-20; 12½ x 28 color (Box 1638)
  - Travelogue posters: “Alhambra, Les Indes Romantiques, Paris”; single panel lithograph poster [very fragile/very poor condition], 1923; 21; 13 x 28 color (Box 1638)
  - Travelogue posters: “Alhambra, Les Indes Romantiques, Paris”; single panel lithograph, 1923; 22; 13 x 28 color (Box 1638)
  - Framed charcoal drawing of Lowell Thomas by James McBey [item is currently located in the Marist College Special Collections hanging storage area], 1919; 23; 23 x 18½ b&w (Box 1638)
  Box 1639
- World War I/Travelogues, 2.3.9
  - Wadi Araba, caravan in distance [index number 1-14] [photograph], 1918; 1; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1639)
  - Wadi Araba, caravan, close-up [index number 1-15] [photograph], 1918; 2; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1639)
  - Airplane at Akaba, two men in cockpits [index number 1-32] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 3; 11 x 14 color (Box 1639)
  - Arab man [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A Sheik of Araby] [index number 1-78] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 4; 11 x 14 color (Box 1639)
  - Bedouin sheik on horse [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Tallal El-Hareidhin of Tafas] [photograph], 1918; 5; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1639)
  - Arab battery in action, sunset, fighting near Damascus [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence’s mountain guns in action] [index number 1-104] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 6; 11 x 14 color (Box 1639)
  - Harry Chase taking motion pictures from armored car [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Mr. Chase opening fire with his cinema camera from the turret of an armored car] [index number 1-106] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 7; 11 x 14 color (Box 1639)
  - Lowell Thomas in pith helmet sits and servant stands in front of tent with cameras and other equipment on the ground [index number 2-3] [photograph], 1918; 8-10; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1639)
  - Patrol of Ford automobiles in Arabian desert (Lowell Thomas note: This goes with Arabian negatives) [index number 2-133] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 11; 11 x 14 color (Box 1639)
  - Lowell Thomas on Arab horse [index number 4-12] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 12; 11 x 14 color (Box 1639)
  - Lowell Thomas on Arab horse [index number 4-12] [photograph], 1918; 13; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1639)
  - Lowell Thomas taking notes alongside a disabled tank near Gaza [index number 4-20] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 14; 11 x 14 color (Box 1639)
  - [left to right] Major Piero Tozzi, Lowell Thomas and Colonel Webb Hayes sit in gondola; gondolier stands at rear [index number 4-26] [hand-colored photograph], 1917; 15; 12 x 17 color (Box 1639)
  - [seated left to right in rear of automobile] Lowell Thomas, Colonel Webb Hayes and Major Piero Tozzi; soldiers on horseback in background [index number 4-27] [hand-colored photograph], 1917; 16; 13 x 16½ color (Box 1639)
  - Lowell Thomas and Italian officer standing before a statue of General von Hindenburg [index number 4-41] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 17; 17 x 13 color (Box 1639)
  - View of Great Pyramid of Giza taken from airplane in flight] [hand-colored photograph], 1918; 18; 11 x 14 color (Box 1639)
  - Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas wearing Kaiser Wilhelm’s helmet [verso: Fran with the Kaiser’s helmet! Brought from Berlin during the 1918-1919 German Revolution after the Kaiser fled] [photograph], circa 1918; 19; 10 x 9½ b&w (Box 1639)
  - Woman stands in doorway amid ruins in Italy [hand-colored photograph], 1917; 20; 17 x 12½ color (Box 1639)
  - Luisa Tetrazzini [caption: To my friends Mr. and Mrs. Lowell Thomas in remembrance of America that I love so much, Luisa Tetrazzini, Roma 23 Giugno 1918] [photograph], 1918 June 23; 21; 17 x 12 b&w (Box 1639)
  Box 1640
- World War I/Travelogues, 2.3.9
  - T. E. Lawrence standing, three quarter length [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The archeologist and poet who turned soldier] [index number 1-42] [photograph], circa 1918-1921; 1; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - T. E. Lawrence and his bodyguard in the desert [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Sidi” Lawrence and his “Sons”] [index number 1-47] [photograph], circa 1918-1921; 2; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe, squatting, full-faced, close-up [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Col. T. E. Lawrence] [index number 1-52] [photograph], circa 1918-1921; 3; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe, squatting, full-faced, close-up [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Col. T. E. Lawrence] [index number 1-54] [photograph], circa 1918-1921; 4; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - T. E. Lawrence in white robe with sword at waist, sitting on floor, side view, right hand on chin [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The dreamer whose dreams came true] [index number 1-58A] [photograph], circa 1918-1921; 5; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas squatting in London Arab [index number 4-4] [photograph], circa 1918-1921; 6; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - T. E. Lawrence sitting beside camel [photograph], circa 1918-1921; 7; 16 x 24½ b&w (Box 1640)
  - T. E. Lawrence, close-up [photograph], circa 1918-1921; 8; 16 x 24 ½ b&w (Box 1640)
  - Malaya travelogue photograph - Lowell Thomas atop elephant, 1921; 9; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Malaya travelogue photograph - tea party at the Roberts’s house with Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, Duncan Roberts and Mrs. Roberts, 1921; 10; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Malaya travelogue photograph - group shot includes Lowell Thomas (left), Harry Chase squatting (right) and Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas standing behind men seated at right, 1921; 11; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Malaya travelogue photograph - outdoor scene, 1921; 12; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Malaya travelogue photograph - outdoor scene, 1921; 13; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Malaya travelogue photograph - Sakai pygmy woman of the Malay jungle, 1921; 14; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Malaya travelogue photograph - Sakai pygmy woman of the Malay jungle, 1921; 15; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Burma travelogue photograph - a river dweller of the upper Irrawaddy, 1921; 16; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Burma travelogue photograph - a leg rower of the Shan states, 1921; 17; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - India travelogue photograph - a Hindu fakir who stands on his head for hours at a time, 1921 - 1922; 18; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)
  - India travelogue photograph - two men sit on a bed of nails, 1921 - 1922; 19; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)
  - India travelogue photograph - irrigating the rice fields near the equator in tropical India at 2 cents per day, 1921 - 1922; 20; 11 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)
  - India travelogue photograph - a duelist of the Himalayas, 1921 - 1922; 21; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Afghanistan travelogue photograph - Afghan man seated with rifle, 1922; 22; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Afghanistan travelogue photograph - Afghan man standing with rifle, 1922; 23; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Afghanistan travelogue photograph - armed Afghan men in fort, 1922; 24; 16 x 20 b&w (Box 1640)
  - Ross Smith travelogue photograph, circa early 1920s; 25; 12 x 14 b&w (Box 1640)